[
    {
        "question": "1. What is WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress, a renowned open-source Content Management System (CMS), empowers users to effortlessly create and manage websites. It has a simple interface that makes it accessible to people who don’t know much about coding. WordPress is suitable for a wide range of websites, including portfolios, business websites, blogs, e-commerce stores, and more, thanks to its versatility and extensive feature set.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. Are there any limitations to a WordPress website?",
        "answer": "Unlock the full potential of WordPress, as it caters to a diverse range of sites, from e-commerce and membership platforms to photo galleries and beyond. With the same HTML code used as any other site, the possibilities are limitless, allowing you to build and customize websites just the way you envision them.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. Differentiate between WordPress.com and WordPress.org.",
        "answer": "WordPress.com is a hosting platform where you can create a website without the need for separate hosting. WordPress.org provides the free WordPress software that you can download and install on your own web hosting.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. List some of the key features of WordPress.",
        "answer": "1) User-Friendly Interface: WordPress provides an intuitive and user-friendly interface, making it easy for users of all levels of technical expertise to manage and update their websites\n2) Themes: WordPress offers a vast collection of themes that allow you to change the look and feel of your website with just a few clicks. You can also customize themes or create your own using HTML, CSS, and PHP.\n3) Plugins: Plugins can be used for SEO optimization, e-commerce, security, contact forms, social media integration, and much more.\n4) User Management: WordPress allows you to create multiple user accounts with different roles and permissions. You can assign specific capabilities to each user, control access levels, and manage user profiles.\n5) SEO-Friendly: WordPress is built with SEO (Search Engine Optimization) in mind. It offers features such as customizable permalinks, meta tags, XML sitemaps, and integration with popular SEO plugins, helping you optimize your website for search engines.\n6) Regular Updates and Community Support: WordPress has a large and active community of developers and users who contribute to its continuous improvement. Regular updates, security patches, and extensive documentation are provided to ensure a secure and up-to-date CMS. \n7) Media Management: WordPress includes a built-in media library where you can upload and manage images, videos, and other media files. You can easily insert media into posts or pages, set featured images, and organize your media files.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What are WordPress Plugins?",
        "answer": "WordPress plugins are extensions or add-ons that enhance the functionality of a WordPress website. They are packages of code that can be easily installed and activated within the WordPress CMS.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are the requirements to run WordPress?",
        "answer": "The requirements to run WordPress include a web server (such as Apache or Nginx), PHP, MySQL or MariaDB, and a domain name.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. Could you Explain Avatar and Gravatar in WordPress?",
        "answer": "In online communications, the user’s profile picture is referred to as an “avatar.” A web-based service called Gravatar lets users use the Avatar image.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are shortcodes in WordPress? Give an example.",
        "answer": "Shortcodes are placeholders that allow users to add dynamic content or functionality to their posts or pages by using a simple code. An example of a shortcode is [ gallery ] for displaying image galleries.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain the difference between WordPress.com and WordPress.org.",
        "answer": "WordPress.com is a hosted platform that lets users build websites and blogs without having to use other hosting services. WordPress.org gives a product that can be downloaded and introduced on a web server, permitting clients to have full command over their site.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. How can you install WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress can be installed by downloading the software from the official website (WordPress.org), uploading the files to a web server, creating a database, and running the installation script.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. How can you create a child theme in WordPress?",
        "answer": "To create a child theme in WordPress, you need to create a new folder in the “wp-content/themes” directory, create a “style.css” file with specific information and a reference to the parent theme, and optionally create a “functions.php” file for additional customization.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Explain the difference between posts and pages in WordPress.",
        "answer": "Posts in WordPress are typically used for blog entries or dynamic content that is displayed in reverse chronological order. Pages, on the other hand, are more suitable for static content like “About” or “Contact” pages that don’t need frequent updates.\nGet 100% Hike!\nMaster Most in Demand Skills Now!\nBy providing your contact details, you agree to our Terms of Use & Privacy Policy",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is a shortcode in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A shortcode in WordPress is a small piece of code enclosed in square brackets. It allows users to add dynamic content or functionality to a post, page, or widget without directly writing code.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. How can you display custom fields in WordPress?",
        "answer": "To display custom fields in WordPress, you can use the get_post_meta() function to retrieve the value of a specific custom field. You can then echo or display it wherever you want it to appear.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. How can you secure your WordPress website?",
        "answer": "WordPress websites can be secured by keeping the WordPress core, themes, and plugins up to date. This is done by using strong passwords, limiting login attempts, implementing\nCheck out our PHP Interview Questions to ace your next interview!",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is a child theme, and why would you use it?",
        "answer": "A child theme is a theme that inherits the functionality and styling of a parent theme. It allows you to make modifications to a theme without directly editing the parent theme files, which helps to preserve your changes during theme updates.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. How can you add a new menu in WordPress?",
        "answer": "To add a new menu in WordPress, you can go to the WordPress dashboard, click on “Appearance” in the sidebar, and then click “Menus.” From there, you can create a new menu, add menu items, and assign the menu to specific locations on your website.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. How can you add an image gallery in a WordPress post or page?",
        "answer": "To add an image gallery in a WordPress post or page, you can use the built-in gallery feature. While editing a post or page, click the “Add Media” button, select the images you want to include in the gallery, and click the “Create Gallery” button.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What is a shortcode in WordPress, and how can you create one?",
        "answer": "Shortcodes in WordPress are placeholders that allow you to dynamically insert pre-defined functionality or content into your posts or pages. Shortcodes are enclosed in square brackets, such as [ gallery ] to display a gallery.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Explain the concept of permalinks in WordPress.",
        "answer": "Permalinks in WordPress refer to the URL structure of individual posts, pages, or other types of content. You can configure the permalink structure in the WordPress dashboard under “Settings” > “Permalinks.”\n\nIntermediate WordPress Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. What are the requirements to install WordPress?",
        "answer": "To install WordPress, you need a domain name and a web hosting provider that supports PHP and MySQL databases.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. How can you create a custom post type in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a custom post type in WordPress by using the register_post_type() function in your theme’s functions.php file or by using a plugin like Custom Post Type UI.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. How can you optimize the performance of a WordPress website?",
        "answer": "Performance optimization techniques for a WordPress website include caching, optimizing images, using a content delivery network (CDN), minifying CSS and JavaScript files, and choosing a reliable hosting provider.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "24. How can you create a custom menu in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a custom menu in WordPress by going to the Appearance > Menus section in the WordPress dashboard. From there, you can create a new menu, add pages or custom links to it, and assign it to a specific menu location.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "25. What is the purpose of the functions.php file in a WordPress theme?",
        "answer": "The functions.php file in a WordPress theme is used to add custom PHP code, functions, or hooks to modify the theme’s functionality or add new features.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "26. How can you set up a static front page in WordPress?",
        "answer": "To set up a static front page in WordPress, you can go to the Settings > Reading section in the WordPress dashboard. You can choose a specific page as the front page and another page as the posts page.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "27. What is the WordPress loop?",
        "answer": "The WordPress loop is a PHP code structure that retrieves and displays posts or other content from the WordPress database. It is used to iterate through the content and display it dynamically.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "28. What is the purpose of the .htaccess file in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The .htaccess file in WordPress is used to configure server-level settings and rules. It is often used for URL rewriting, enabling gzip compression, setting cache expiration, and enhancing security.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "29. How can you create a custom taxonomy in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a custom taxonomy in WordPress by using the register_taxonomy() function in your theme’s functions.php file or by using a plugin like Custom Post Type UI.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "30. What is the difference between actions and filters in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Actions and filters are two types of hooks in WordPress. Actions allow you to add or modify functionality at specific points in the WordPress execution flow, while filters allow you to modify data before it is displayed or used.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "31. How can you display related posts in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can display related posts in WordPress by using plugins that analyze the content and suggest related posts based on categories, tags, or other criteria. You can also create custom queries or use the get_related_posts() function to fetch related posts.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "32. What is the purpose of the wp-config.php file in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The wp-config.php file in WordPress contains important configuration settings for your website, such as database connection details, security keys, and other settings. It is generated during the WordPress installation process.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "33. How can you create a custom login page in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a custom login page in WordPress by creating a new PHP file and using the wp_login_form() function to display the login form. You can also customize the login page using plugins or by modifying the theme’s files.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "34. What is the difference between a widget-ready area and a sidebar in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A widget-ready area is a specific section of a theme that allows you to add widgets, while a sidebar is a common widget-ready area typically located on the left or right side of a webpage. Sidebars are often used for navigation menus or additional content.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "35. What is the purpose of the wp_enqueue_script() function in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The wp_enqueue_script() function in WordPress is used to register and enqueue JavaScript files. It ensures that scripts are loaded efficiently and avoids conflicts with other plugins or themes.\n\nAdvanced WordPress Interview Questions",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "36. What is the purpose of the wp_head() and wp_footer() functions in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The wp_head() function is used to output the HTML head section of a WordPress theme, which includes meta tags, stylesheets, and JavaScript files. The wp_footer() function outputs the closing body and HTML tags, as well as any scripts that need to be placed at the end of the page.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "37. What is the purpose of the wp_query() function in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The wp_query() function in WordPress is used to create custom queries to retrieve posts or other content from the database. It provides flexibility in specifying various parameters such as post type, taxonomy, and metadata.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "38. How can you create a multilingual website in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a multilingual website in WordPress by using plugins like WPML (WordPress Multilingual Plugin) or Polylang. These plugins provide translation management and language switching functionality.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "39. What is the purpose of the functions get_header() and get_footer() in WordPress?",
        "answer": "In WordPress themes, the functions get_header() and get_footer() are utilized to incorporate the header and footer template files, respectively, enhancing the design and layout of the website. They allow for modular development and easy updating of these sections.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "40. How can you optimize images in WordPress for better performance?",
        "answer": "You can optimize images in WordPress by using compression techniques, such as using image optimization plugins, resizing images to appropriate dimensions, and choosing the right file formats (JPEG, PNG, etc.) based on the content.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "41. What is the difference between a static website and a WordPress website?",
        "answer": "A static website consists of fixed HTML pages that need to be manually edited to make changes. A WordPress website, on the other hand, is dynamic and allows content to be managed through a CMS, making it easier to update and add new content.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "42. What is a customizer in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The customizer in WordPress is a feature that allows users to customize various aspects of their website’s appearance and functionality in real-time. It provides a user-friendly interface to make changes to themes, widgets, menus, and other settings.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "43. What is the purpose of the wp_nav_menu() function in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The wp_nav_menu() function in WordPress is used to display a navigation menu in a theme. It allows you to create menus and assign them to specific locations in your theme.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "44. What is the purpose of the WP_Query class in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The WP_Query class in WordPress is used to query and retrieve posts or other content from the database. It provides a wide range of parameters and options to customize the query and retrieve specific content based on various criteria.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "45. How can you create a custom widget area in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can create a custom widget area in WordPress by adding a new section of code to your theme’s functions.php file that registers a new widget area. Then, you can display this widget area in your theme’s template files using the dynamic_sidebar() function.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "46. What is the purpose of the do_shortcode() function in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The do_shortcode() function in WordPress is used to execute shortcodes programmatically. It allows you to dynamically generate and display shortcode content within your theme’s template files or in other areas where shortcodes are not automatically parsed.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. How can you set up a contact form in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can set up a contact form in WordPress by using plugins like Contact Form 7, WPForms, or Gravity Forms. These plugins provide an easy way to create and customize contact forms that can be inserted into your website using shortcode or widget.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "48. What is the purpose of the excerpt in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The excerpt in WordPress is a short summary or teaser of a post’s content. It is often used to provide a preview of the post on archive pages or in search results. By default, WordPress generates an excerpt automatically based on the content, but you can also manually define a custom excerpt.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "49. How can you back up a WordPress website?",
        "answer": "You can back up a WordPress website by using plugins that automate the backup process, such as UpdraftPlus or BackupBuddy. These plugins allow you to schedule backups and store them locally or in cloud storage services. Additionally, you can manually back up your website by exporting the database and files through the hosting control panel.",
        "reference": "intellipaat.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. How to increase WordPress website security?",
        "answer": "Despite being a safe CMS (content management system), WordPress is susceptible to attacks, just like any other CMS. WordPress security can be enhanced in many ways, as follows: Login procedures should be secure.\nConsider using a secure WordPress hosting provider.\nUpdate the WordPress version.\nUpgrade the PHP version.\nDownload and install security plugins.\nSelect a secure theme for WordPress.\nEnable SSL (Secure Socket Layer) or HTTPS (HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure) for your site.\nSet up a firewall.\nMake a backup of your site.\nManage user permissions on WordPress.\nChange the default login URL of WordPress.\nDisable xmlrpc.php file.\nDisable editing files within the WordPress dashboard.\nModify the database file prefix.\nDelete the default WordPress administrator account.\nHide the WordPress version. Login procedures should be secure. Consider using a secure WordPress hosting provider. Update the WordPress version. Upgrade the PHP version. Download and install security plugins. Select a secure theme for WordPress. Enable SSL (Secure Socket Layer) or HTTPS (HyperText Transfer Protocol Secure) for your site. Set up a firewall. Make a backup of your site. Manage user permissions on WordPress. Change the default login URL of WordPress. Disable xmlrpc.php file. Disable editing files within the WordPress dashboard. Modify the database file prefix. Delete the default WordPress administrator account. Hide the WordPress version.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is WordPress?",
        "answer": "The WordPress content management system (CMS) is a free, open-source software application. With this tool, you can control the entire process of creating and publishing web content as well as managing their websites. You can easily manage content on your website using a content management system, even if you have no experience in programming. Therefore, WordPress makes it possible for anyone - even those who aren't developers - to build a website. Almost all web hosts support PHP and MySQL, which are used by WordPress. WordPress is a flexible CMS that can be used for virtually any type of website, including blogging, e-commerce, government, and business sites. With its flexibility and usability, WordPress is a perfect solution for large and small websites. PHP PHP MySQL MySQL",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are some of the essential features of WordPress?",
        "answer": "The following are some of the essential features of WordPress: Easily manage the content of your website whenever you want. \nInstalling and upgrading WordPress has never been a problem. A number of web hosts offer one-click installations of WordPress that let you set it up in just a few seconds.\nCreate as many pages, posts, products, and more as you want - You can upload files, text, images, links, and embed media to your pages whenever you want.\nThe WordPress platform lets you build any type of website, whether it's a personal blog or website, a portfolio, a photoblog, a business website, an online magazine, a news publication, a government website, or even an online community.\nWith WordPress, you get three default themes, but if they aren't perfect for you, you can find thousands of other themes in the theme directory.\nWordPress has a plugin directory with thousands of plugins for every feature that isn't in the core.\nIt's easy to add, edit, or remove additional editors to allow others in your organization to manage content on your website. Easily manage the content of your website whenever you want. Installing and upgrading WordPress has never been a problem. A number of web hosts offer one-click installations of WordPress that let you set it up in just a few seconds. Create as many pages, posts, products, and more as you want - You can upload files, text, images, links, and embed media to your pages whenever you want. The WordPress platform lets you build any type of website, whether it's a personal blog or website, a portfolio, a photoblog, a business website, an online magazine, a news publication, a government website, or even an online community. With WordPress, you get three default themes, but if they aren't perfect for you, you can find thousands of other themes in the theme directory. WordPress has a plugin directory with thousands of plugins for every feature that isn't in the core. It's easy to add, edit, or remove additional editors to allow others in your organization to manage content on your website.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What are WordPress Plugins?",
        "answer": "WordPress plugins are individual pieces of software that allow you to add additional functionality to your website. All of these software pieces can be installed on your WordPress website. By using plugins, you can extend or add new functionality to your website, enabling you to easily create any type of website, from e-commerce to directories. Plugins can tweak your site in minor ways or make massive changes, depending on the features. By using a plugin, you could, for example, create a fully multilingual site or add a WhatsApp share button. Many plugins can help you add a contact form to your website, create customizable image galleries, and link to social media. You have a lot of options to choose from, both free and premium.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. List some of the plugins that come with WordPress.",
        "answer": "The following are the top ten most popular WordPress plugins of all time, based on actual downloads from WordPress.org. Yoast SEO\nWordfence Security\nAkismet\nContact Form 7\nGoogle Analytics for WordPress\nJetpack\nElementor\nWPForms\nWooCommerce\nAll in One SEO Pack Yoast SEO Wordfence Security Akismet Contact Form 7 Google Analytics for WordPress Jetpack Elementor WPForms WooCommerce All in One SEO Pack",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. How to create a plugin in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The following steps will guide you through creating your first plugin: Connect to your site via FTP (File Transfer Protocol).\nNavigate to the WordPress plugins folder after gaining access to your site via FTP. This folder is usually located in /wp-content/plugins. Connect to your site via FTP (File Transfer Protocol). Navigate to the WordPress plugins folder after gaining access to your site via FTP. This folder is usually located in /wp-content/plugins.   After you've navigated into the plugins folder, you can create a folder of your own. Create a new folder with a unique name that uses lowercase letters and dashes, for example, first_plugin. Once you've done that, choose your new folder and continue. After you've navigated into the plugins folder, you can create a folder of your own. Create a new folder with a unique name that uses lowercase letters and dashes, for example, first_plugin. Once you've done that, choose your new folder and continue.   You will then need to create the main plugin file. You will then need to create the main plugin file.   Then, create a file named very-first-plugin.php in your new plugin folder. Then, create a file named very-first-plugin.php in your new plugin folder.   The plugin information can now be copied and pasted into your newly created main plugin file. Make sure to modify plugin details such as Plugin URL and Plugin Name. The plugin information can now be copied and pasted into your newly created main plugin file. Make sure to modify plugin details such as Plugin URL and Plugin Name.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What limitations does the WordPress website have?",
        "answer": "The use of WordPress is not limited. Depending on your needs, it can be used for anything, from e-commerce sites to membership sites. The downsides of WordPress include: Adding too many plugins can make the website hard to load and run.\nMaking changes or modifications to a WordPress site requires PHP knowledge.\nIt is sometimes necessary to update WordPress to keep it compatible with the latest browsers and mobile devices. Changing the version of WordPress leads to data loss, so making a backup copy is essential.\nIt is very difficult to modify or format the graphic images and tables. Adding too many plugins can make the website hard to load and run. Making changes or modifications to a WordPress site requires PHP knowledge. It is sometimes necessary to update WordPress to keep it compatible with the latest browsers and mobile devices. Changing the version of WordPress leads to data loss, so making a backup copy is essential. It is very difficult to modify or format the graphic images and tables.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What is required to run WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress has the following minimal requirements: PHP version 7.2 or higher.\nA MySQL version of 5.6 or higher OR a MariaDB version of 10.0 or higher.\nSupport for HTTP.\nThe best servers for running WordPress are Nginx or Apache, but any server that supports MySQL and PHP will work. PHP version 7.2 or higher. A MySQL version of 5.6 or higher OR a MariaDB version of 10.0 or higher. Support for HTTP. The best servers for running WordPress are Nginx or Apache, but any server that supports MySQL and PHP will work.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. How many tables are there by default in WordPress?",
        "answer": "In WordPress databases, the shelves are called tables. By default, WordPress websites contain 12 tables. Only certain data can be stored in each table. WordPress comments tables, for example, contain information regarding IP addresses, comment author slugs, etc., of people who have commented on a post. In this way, data can be stored and retrieved more quickly.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. In WordPress, how can we change the table prefix ( wp_ )?",
        "answer": "You can change and rename the WordPress database prefix in several ways. Change the table prefix in wp-config.php Change the table prefix in wp-config.php Go to the WordPress root directory and open the wp-config.php file. Change the prefix of the table \"wp_\" to whatever you wish, for example, \"wp_a564356_\". Therefore, the line would look as follows: $table_prefix  = 'wp_a564356_'; Change the table prefix in the database Change the table prefix in the database In PhpMyAdmin, open the database.\nSelect all tables that begin with the wp_ prefix.\nClick With selected to display a drop-down menu. Select Replace table prefix from the list.\nIn the From-field, enter wp_. In the To-field, type the new name.\nThen click Continue to make the changes. In PhpMyAdmin, open the database. Select all tables that begin with the wp_ prefix. Click With selected to display a drop-down menu. Select Replace table prefix from the list. In the From-field, enter wp_. In the To-field, type the new name. Then click Continue to make the changes.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are the basic steps we should take when our WordPress website is hacked?",
        "answer": "Since WordPress is one of the most popular CMS platforms on the web, its security is paramount. Upon analyzing the existing loopholes, standard security policies should be implemented in WordPress to protect WordPress data. The steps that must be taken when your WordPress platform is hacked are as follows: Keep calm and seek an optimal solution.\nTrack down the hack.\nContact your web hosting provider.\nGet an InfoSec expert to help you.\nDownload and install a security plugin, such as WordPress security.\nLocate, scan, and fix/remove malware.\nEnsure that your access permissions are correct.\nAlso, update WordPress to its latest version. \nUpdate all user IDs and passwords.\nCheck to make sure that your plugins and themes are up to date. Keep calm and seek an optimal solution. Track down the hack. Contact your web hosting provider. Get an InfoSec expert to help you. Download and install a security plugin, such as WordPress security. Locate, scan, and fix/remove malware. Ensure that your access permissions are correct. Also, update WordPress to its latest version. Update all user IDs and passwords. Check to make sure that your plugins and themes are up to date.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. How to update the WordPress website?",
        "answer": "You can update your WordPress site in two simple ways: automatically and manually. Automatic Method (One-click update): This is the easiest way to upgrade your WordPress version. It is as easy as clicking a button, and the installation will take only a few minutes. Automatic Method (One-click update): Go to the WordPress admin dashboard and see if you have a new release available. To initiate the website update, click Please update now. On the Updates page, you'll need to click on the Update Now button again. Go to the WordPress admin dashboard and see if you have a new release available. To initiate the website update, click Please update now. On the Updates page, you'll need to click on the Update Now button again.   Minor updates are indicated by a success message and options for plugin and theme updates. A welcome screen will, however, summarize what has been upgraded for major releases. Minor updates are indicated by a success message and options for plugin and theme updates. A welcome screen will, however, summarize what has been upgraded for major releases.   Now that you have updated WordPress, you can ensure that all of your themes and plugins are compatible with the new version. Now that you have updated WordPress, you can ensure that all of your themes and plugins are compatible with the new version. Manual Method: You will need to manually upload WordPress files using FTP (File Transfer Protocol). In case the first method doesn't work, you can use this method. Manual Method: Update WordPress to the latest version. Click on the Download button on the WordPress download page. Update WordPress to the latest version. Click on the Download button on the WordPress download page.   WordPress will now be downloaded to your browser as a zip file. Extract the zip file once it has been downloaded. There will be a WordPress folder inside, containing all the WordPress files required for the update.\nAccess your WordPress site through FileZilla or either through your preferred FTP client.\nLook at the existing wp-admin directory and wp-includes directory on the remote side (right side of the panel) and right-click to delete/remove them. WordPress will now be downloaded to your browser as a zip file. Extract the zip file once it has been downloaded. There will be a WordPress folder inside, containing all the WordPress files required for the update. Access your WordPress site through FileZilla or either through your preferred FTP client. Look at the existing wp-admin directory and wp-includes directory on the remote side (right side of the panel) and right-click to delete/remove them.   Select the new wp-includes and wp-admin folders from the left-hand side of the panel (local site), then click Upload. Select the new wp-includes and wp-admin folders from the left-hand side of the panel (local site), then click Upload.   The remaining WordPress files must be uploaded from your computer to the web host directory.\nUpload the new WordPress files to the server by overwriting the old ones.\nCheck if you've successfully completed the WordPress updates via FTP for your website by navigating to yoursite.com/wp-admin/upgrade.php/. The remaining WordPress files must be uploaded from your computer to the web host directory. Upload the new WordPress files to the server by overwriting the old ones. Check if you've successfully completed the WordPress updates via FTP for your website by navigating to yoursite.com/wp-admin/upgrade.php/.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What do you mean by posts and pages in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The difference between posts and pages is that posts are more timely and regularly updated, while pages are static. It is possible to have any number of pages and posts on your website.   WordPress Post: You can think of a WordPress post as the blog aspect of the website. In most cases, these are informational updates or news about a particular topic. It is possible to tag, categorize, and archive posts on your site. Their content is dynamic and constantly changing.\nWordPress Pages: WordPress offers another prebuilt post type called pages. A page is similar to a post in that it has a title and body text, but it is different. In general, we add content to pages that don't need to be updated frequently. A page is similar to a post in that it has a title and body text, but it is different. Page content represents static content, such as the \"About Us\" page, the \"TOCs\", the \"Contact us\" page, and the \"Write for Us\" page. WordPress Post: You can think of a WordPress post as the blog aspect of the website. In most cases, these are informational updates or news about a particular topic. It is possible to tag, categorize, and archive posts on your site. Their content is dynamic and constantly changing. WordPress Post: WordPress Pages: WordPress offers another prebuilt post type called pages. A page is similar to a post in that it has a title and body text, but it is different. In general, we add content to pages that don't need to be updated frequently. A page is similar to a post in that it has a title and body text, but it is different. Page content represents static content, such as the \"About Us\" page, the \"TOCs\", the \"Contact us\" page, and the \"Write for Us\" page. WordPress Pages:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Can you create custom post types in WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress developers are able to create custom post types. The register_post_type() function may be used to add a custom post type. Plugins allow us to create custom post types as well. register_post_type() Custom Post Type UI\nCustom Field Custom Post Type UI Custom Field",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Where is the WordPress content stored?",
        "answer": "Wp_posts is a table in your MySQL database that holds the content of your WordPress posts and pages. WordPress displays your content using dynamic PHP templates, so it doesn't store a separate HTML file for each page. In the database, you can also find \"Pages\" (or other custom post types available in WordPress) in the wp_posts table. Typically, these can be accessed through phpMyAdmin.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Are deactivated plugins likely to slow down WordPress websites?",
        "answer": "No, Plugins that are inactive or deactivated don't slow down WordPress. Deactivating a WordPress plugin simply turns it off. The plugin is still installed on your site, so you can activate it again if need be. Uninstalling a plugin, on the other hand, removes it from your website completely. If there are deactivated plugins preset, they will be treated as if they didn't exist. WordPress will load only the active plugins.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is a loop in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A PHP code for displaying WordPress posts is referred to as a loop or WordPress code. The WordPress themes display posts using a loop on the web pages of the website. These loops include functions that display the posts. One of the most important components of the WordPress code is its Loop, which contains several Template Tags for publishing, formatting, and organizing post content. By default, the WordPress loop includes the following information for each post: Title (the_title())\nTime (the_time())\nCategories (the_category()). Title (the_title()) Time (the_time()) Categories (the_category()).",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. How can comments be disabled in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Disabling comments in WordPress can be done in several ways. You can disable comments in future posts, for instance. Navigate to admin panel -> settings -> discussion tab. Uncheck the \"Allow people to post comments on new articles\" option and then click on \"Save Changes\". By doing this, all comments on your future posts will be disabled.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What are config files in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Wp-config.php is a core WordPress file. Information pertaining to the database is contained in this file, such as its name, username, password, and host (typically localhost). WordPress uses this information to store and retrieve data ( such as users, posts, settings, etc.) from the database. WordPress does not include the file wp-config.php in its default download package. It contains a file named wp-config-sample.php, that can be renamed to wp-config.php.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Is there any way to make other pages appear on the front page in WordPress?",
        "answer": "To make your static page a front page you have to follow these steps: Go to the Admin Panel and click on \"Static Page\".\nYou can select your front page in the \"Front page\" section.\nFrom now on, your selected page will serve as your default front page. Go to the Admin Panel and click on \"Static Page\". You can select your front page in the \"Front page\" section. From now on, your selected page will serve as your default front page.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Can you tell me how to create a page template?",
        "answer": "Creating custom templates can serve a number of purposes, such as making a different layout from the home page or displaying custom post types like news. Add a news.php file to the theme folder.\nAdd the get_header() and get_footer() functions to the news.php page.\nAdd them at the top. The template name is now \"News Template\". Add a news.php file to the theme folder. Add the get_header() and get_footer() functions to the news.php page. Add them at the top. The template name is now \"News Template\".",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Explain the term template tags in WordPress.",
        "answer": "Template tags are an immensely valuable part of WordPress, especially when developing themes. A WordPress template tag is a PHP function that generates and displays content dynamically on a website. Themes in WordPress contain different templates that theme developers use to display dynamic data. The WordPress themes can use several built-in template tags. The template tags are contained in 9 files in the wp-includes directory. wp-includes/general-template.php\nwp-includes/link-template.php\nwp-includes/category-template.php\nwp-includes/nav-menu-template.php\nwp-includes/author-template.php\nwp-includes/post-template.php\nwp-includes/post-thumbnail-template.php\nwp-includes/comment-template.php\nwp-includes/bookmark-template.php wp-includes/general-template.php wp-includes/link-template.php wp-includes/category-template.php wp-includes/nav-menu-template.php wp-includes/author-template.php wp-includes/post-template.php wp-includes/post-thumbnail-template.php wp-includes/comment-template.php wp-includes/bookmark-template.php",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. List a few template tags that can be used in WordPress.",
        "answer": "The following are some template tags you can use in WordPress. get_header()\nget_footer()\nget_sidebar()\nwp_login_url()\nget_calendar()\nallowed_tags()\nthe_author()\nget_the_author()\nwp_list_bookmarks()\nget_bookmark()\nthe_category()\nthe_category_rss()\ncomment_author()\ncomment_author_email()\nthe_permalink()\nuser_trailingslashit()\npermalink_anchor()\npost_class()\npost_password_required()\nget_post_thumbnail_id()\nthe_post_thumbnail()\nwp_nav_menu()\nwalk_nav_menu_tree(), etc. get_header() get_footer() get_sidebar() wp_login_url() get_calendar() allowed_tags() the_author() get_the_author() wp_list_bookmarks() get_bookmark() the_category() the_category_rss() comment_author() comment_author_email() the_permalink() user_trailingslashit() permalink_anchor() post_class() post_password_required() get_post_thumbnail_id() the_post_thumbnail() wp_nav_menu() walk_nav_menu_tree(), etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. State the difference between Wordpress and Wix.",
        "answer": "Both WordPress and Wix are platforms for building websites, but each has completely different approaches. while Wix is a website builder.    Wordpress Wix\nWordPress is an open-source content management system (CMS) that lets you easily create content pages and publish them online. A simple and easy-to-use website builder, Wix allows you to build your website from scratch with flexible designs, which makes it ideal for portfolio-style websites.\nAs you begin using the CMS, it may be intimidating since it does not hold your hand too much.  Getting started with Wix is a straightforward process. \nWordPress offers only a few official themes on its site.  There are hundreds of website templates offered by Wix - all of which are responsive - and its editor enables users to add their personal touches, so that is an excellent start.\nAs a WordPress user, you bear the brunt of the responsibility of securing your website. Essentially, you need to stay on top of core updates, watch out for various errors, choose the right host, and take care of everything else. In terms of security, Wix goes ahead and takes care of it all on its own, aside from the basics such as choosing a strong password or using two-factor authentication. It is highly secure because Wix is a closed system and Wix's able team provides server maintenance and script updates.\nBesides its knowledge base, WordPress doesn't provide any specialized support.  Wix provides both a comprehensive knowledge base as well as telephone support. Wordpress Wix\nWordPress is an open-source content management system (CMS) that lets you easily create content pages and publish them online. A simple and easy-to-use website builder, Wix allows you to build your website from scratch with flexible designs, which makes it ideal for portfolio-style websites.\nAs you begin using the CMS, it may be intimidating since it does not hold your hand too much.  Getting started with Wix is a straightforward process. \nWordPress offers only a few official themes on its site.  There are hundreds of website templates offered by Wix - all of which are responsive - and its editor enables users to add their personal touches, so that is an excellent start.\nAs a WordPress user, you bear the brunt of the responsibility of securing your website. Essentially, you need to stay on top of core updates, watch out for various errors, choose the right host, and take care of everything else. In terms of security, Wix goes ahead and takes care of it all on its own, aside from the basics such as choosing a strong password or using two-factor authentication. It is highly secure because Wix is a closed system and Wix's able team provides server maintenance and script updates.\nBesides its knowledge base, WordPress doesn't provide any specialized support.  Wix provides both a comprehensive knowledge base as well as telephone support. Wordpress Wix Wordpress Wix Wordpress Wix WordPress is an open-source content management system (CMS) that lets you easily create content pages and publish them online. A simple and easy-to-use website builder, Wix allows you to build your website from scratch with flexible designs, which makes it ideal for portfolio-style websites.\nAs you begin using the CMS, it may be intimidating since it does not hold your hand too much.  Getting started with Wix is a straightforward process. \nWordPress offers only a few official themes on its site.  There are hundreds of website templates offered by Wix - all of which are responsive - and its editor enables users to add their personal touches, so that is an excellent start.\nAs a WordPress user, you bear the brunt of the responsibility of securing your website. Essentially, you need to stay on top of core updates, watch out for various errors, choose the right host, and take care of everything else. In terms of security, Wix goes ahead and takes care of it all on its own, aside from the basics such as choosing a strong password or using two-factor authentication. It is highly secure because Wix is a closed system and Wix's able team provides server maintenance and script updates.\nBesides its knowledge base, WordPress doesn't provide any specialized support.  Wix provides both a comprehensive knowledge base as well as telephone support. WordPress is an open-source content management system (CMS) that lets you easily create content pages and publish them online. A simple and easy-to-use website builder, Wix allows you to build your website from scratch with flexible designs, which makes it ideal for portfolio-style websites. WordPress is an open-source content management system (CMS) that lets you easily create content pages and publish them online. A simple and easy-to-use website builder, Wix allows you to build your website from scratch with flexible designs, which makes it ideal for portfolio-style websites. As you begin using the CMS, it may be intimidating since it does not hold your hand too much.  Getting started with Wix is a straightforward process. As you begin using the CMS, it may be intimidating since it does not hold your hand too much. Getting started with Wix is a straightforward process. WordPress offers only a few official themes on its site.  There are hundreds of website templates offered by Wix - all of which are responsive - and its editor enables users to add their personal touches, so that is an excellent start. WordPress offers only a few official themes on its site. There are hundreds of website templates offered by Wix - all of which are responsive - and its editor enables users to add their personal touches, so that is an excellent start. As a WordPress user, you bear the brunt of the responsibility of securing your website. Essentially, you need to stay on top of core updates, watch out for various errors, choose the right host, and take care of everything else. In terms of security, Wix goes ahead and takes care of it all on its own, aside from the basics such as choosing a strong password or using two-factor authentication. It is highly secure because Wix is a closed system and Wix's able team provides server maintenance and script updates. As a WordPress user, you bear the brunt of the responsibility of securing your website. Essentially, you need to stay on top of core updates, watch out for various errors, choose the right host, and take care of everything else. In terms of security, Wix goes ahead and takes care of it all on its own, aside from the basics such as choosing a strong password or using two-factor authentication. It is highly secure because Wix is a closed system and Wix's able team provides server maintenance and script updates. Besides its knowledge base, WordPress doesn't provide any specialized support.  Wix provides both a comprehensive knowledge base as well as telephone support. Besides its knowledge base, WordPress doesn't provide any specialized support. Wix provides both a comprehensive knowledge base as well as telephone support.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What do you mean by WordPress Hooks?",
        "answer": "Whenever you wish to alter or customize something in WordPress, you can almost certainly make use of a hook. WordPress hooks enable you to manipulate the behavior of a procedure without having to modify the WordPress core files. With hooks, you can modify or add new features to WordPress without modifying the core files.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is Action and Filter Hooks?",
        "answer": "Action and Filter are types of WordPress Hooks. Action Hooks: Actions enable you to perform a task at predefined points during the WordPress runtime. In the WordPress code, actions are defined as follows: Action Hooks: Actions enable you to perform a task at predefined points during the WordPress runtime. In the WordPress code, actions are defined as follows: Action Hooks: do_action( 'action_name', [optional_arguments] ); do_action( 'action_name', [optional_arguments] ); Here, the 'action_name' string represents the name of the action. If you would like to pass additional arguments to the callback function, you can specify the [optional_arguments] variable. When no value is specified, this field is empty by default. Filter Hooks: Filters allow you to modify and return any data processed by WordPress. In the WordPress code, filters are defined as follows: Filter Hooks: Filters allow you to modify and return any data processed by WordPress. In the WordPress code, filters are defined as follows: Filter Hooks: apply_filters( 'filter_name', 'value_to_be_filtered', [optional_arguments] ); apply_filters( 'filter_name', 'value_to_be_filtered', [optional_arguments] ); Here, the ‘filter_name’ string represents the name of the filter. 'value_to_be_filtered' represents the value that has to be filtered and returned. In the same way as actions, the [optional_arguments] variable can pass additional arguments.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Why WordPress is considered better than CMS?",
        "answer": "WordPress is the most popular platform because it's easy to use for non-developers to create professional websites. In comparison with most CMS, it is easier to master WordPress; anyone can build a powerful website that is easy to maintain without much effort. A wide range of organizations uses it, from the Rolling Stones to MSNBC to the Sweden government. WordPress is easy to set up and use.\nWordPress comes with built-in SEO enhancements. It is particularly effective when it comes to promoting SEO best practices.\nYou can customize your site's appearance with thousands of graphics templates in WordPress.\nWordPress offers you a lot of design flexibility. Instead of using a single design layout for your entire website, you can use different design layouts if you wish.\nWordPress is constantly adding new features, better tools, and new plugins that can be installed with just a click of a mouse.\nYou can easily customize it (even if you aren't a developer).\nYou do not have to be a security expert. WordPress has always prioritized security above all else. WordPress is easy to set up and use. WordPress comes with built-in SEO enhancements. It is particularly effective when it comes to promoting SEO best practices. You can customize your site's appearance with thousands of graphics templates in WordPress. WordPress offers you a lot of design flexibility. Instead of using a single design layout for your entire website, you can use different design layouts if you wish. WordPress is constantly adding new features, better tools, and new plugins that can be installed with just a click of a mouse. You can easily customize it (even if you aren't a developer). You do not have to be a security expert. WordPress has always prioritized security above all else.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. State the difference between WordPress.com and WordPress.org.",
        "answer": "Differences between WordPress.org and WordPress.com are as follows: Wordpress.org WordPress.com\nWordPress.org allows you to host your site. You'll have to buy your hosting service and install WordPress on that server. WordPress.com, on the other hand, handles all of this for you. All you have to do is register/create an account and you can begin building.\nWordPress.org is likely the better choice if you are interested in making money from your website. There are no restrictions on how you can monetize your content, such as adding affiliate links or creating a membership website. Also, you can use advertising plugins like Advanced Ads to manage your campaigns directly from your WordPress dashboard. WordPress.com, however, makes monetizing your website more difficult. First and foremost, you will need to subscribe to the Business plan or higher to access features such as Google Adsense or eCommerce capabilities. Furthermore, WordPress.com limits affiliate marketing. Users have been prohibited from using the platform to promote affiliate products primarily.\nTechnical support is not provided by WordPress.org. If you prefer, you can browse the support forums or read the documentation. Depending on the plan you choose, WordPress.com provides you with varying levels of technical support. While all plans include email assistance, you'll need a Premium plan to access live chat assistance.\nYou can choose from thousands of plugins and themes on WordPress.org. With WordPress.com, you can only use plugins if you have a Business plan or higher. Advanced customization features are not available without a Premium package. \nYou can almost completely control your SEO strategies with WordPress.org. Yoast SEO is a plugin that can help you optimize your posts and pages for selected keywords. WordPress.com, on the other hand, has limited options for SEO. For Google Analytics integration, you will need a Premium subscription. Further, advanced SEO tools aren't available without a Business plan or higher. Thus, your website can't be optimized by cheaper packages. Wordpress.org WordPress.com\nWordPress.org allows you to host your site. You'll have to buy your hosting service and install WordPress on that server. WordPress.com, on the other hand, handles all of this for you. All you have to do is register/create an account and you can begin building.\nWordPress.org is likely the better choice if you are interested in making money from your website. There are no restrictions on how you can monetize your content, such as adding affiliate links or creating a membership website. Also, you can use advertising plugins like Advanced Ads to manage your campaigns directly from your WordPress dashboard. WordPress.com, however, makes monetizing your website more difficult. First and foremost, you will need to subscribe to the Business plan or higher to access features such as Google Adsense or eCommerce capabilities. Furthermore, WordPress.com limits affiliate marketing. Users have been prohibited from using the platform to promote affiliate products primarily.\nTechnical support is not provided by WordPress.org. If you prefer, you can browse the support forums or read the documentation. Depending on the plan you choose, WordPress.com provides you with varying levels of technical support. While all plans include email assistance, you'll need a Premium plan to access live chat assistance.\nYou can choose from thousands of plugins and themes on WordPress.org. With WordPress.com, you can only use plugins if you have a Business plan or higher. Advanced customization features are not available without a Premium package. \nYou can almost completely control your SEO strategies with WordPress.org. Yoast SEO is a plugin that can help you optimize your posts and pages for selected keywords. WordPress.com, on the other hand, has limited options for SEO. For Google Analytics integration, you will need a Premium subscription. Further, advanced SEO tools aren't available without a Business plan or higher. Thus, your website can't be optimized by cheaper packages. Wordpress.org WordPress.com Wordpress.org WordPress.com Wordpress.org WordPress.com WordPress.org allows you to host your site. You'll have to buy your hosting service and install WordPress on that server. WordPress.com, on the other hand, handles all of this for you. All you have to do is register/create an account and you can begin building.\nWordPress.org is likely the better choice if you are interested in making money from your website. There are no restrictions on how you can monetize your content, such as adding affiliate links or creating a membership website. Also, you can use advertising plugins like Advanced Ads to manage your campaigns directly from your WordPress dashboard. WordPress.com, however, makes monetizing your website more difficult. First and foremost, you will need to subscribe to the Business plan or higher to access features such as Google Adsense or eCommerce capabilities. Furthermore, WordPress.com limits affiliate marketing. Users have been prohibited from using the platform to promote affiliate products primarily.\nTechnical support is not provided by WordPress.org. If you prefer, you can browse the support forums or read the documentation. Depending on the plan you choose, WordPress.com provides you with varying levels of technical support. While all plans include email assistance, you'll need a Premium plan to access live chat assistance.\nYou can choose from thousands of plugins and themes on WordPress.org. With WordPress.com, you can only use plugins if you have a Business plan or higher. Advanced customization features are not available without a Premium package. \nYou can almost completely control your SEO strategies with WordPress.org. Yoast SEO is a plugin that can help you optimize your posts and pages for selected keywords. WordPress.com, on the other hand, has limited options for SEO. For Google Analytics integration, you will need a Premium subscription. Further, advanced SEO tools aren't available without a Business plan or higher. Thus, your website can't be optimized by cheaper packages. WordPress.org allows you to host your site. You'll have to buy your hosting service and install WordPress on that server. WordPress.com, on the other hand, handles all of this for you. All you have to do is register/create an account and you can begin building. WordPress.org allows you to host your site. You'll have to buy your hosting service and install WordPress on that server. WordPress.com, on the other hand, handles all of this for you. All you have to do is register/create an account and you can begin building. WordPress.org is likely the better choice if you are interested in making money from your website. There are no restrictions on how you can monetize your content, such as adding affiliate links or creating a membership website. Also, you can use advertising plugins like Advanced Ads to manage your campaigns directly from your WordPress dashboard. WordPress.com, however, makes monetizing your website more difficult. First and foremost, you will need to subscribe to the Business plan or higher to access features such as Google Adsense or eCommerce capabilities. Furthermore, WordPress.com limits affiliate marketing. Users have been prohibited from using the platform to promote affiliate products primarily. WordPress.org is likely the better choice if you are interested in making money from your website. There are no restrictions on how you can monetize your content, such as adding affiliate links or creating a membership website. Also, you can use advertising plugins like Advanced Ads to manage your campaigns directly from your WordPress dashboard. WordPress.com, however, makes monetizing your website more difficult. First and foremost, you will need to subscribe to the Business plan or higher to access features such as Google Adsense or eCommerce capabilities. Furthermore, WordPress.com limits affiliate marketing. Users have been prohibited from using the platform to promote affiliate products primarily. Technical support is not provided by WordPress.org. If you prefer, you can browse the support forums or read the documentation. Depending on the plan you choose, WordPress.com provides you with varying levels of technical support. While all plans include email assistance, you'll need a Premium plan to access live chat assistance. Technical support is not provided by WordPress.org. If you prefer, you can browse the support forums or read the documentation. Depending on the plan you choose, WordPress.com provides you with varying levels of technical support. While all plans include email assistance, you'll need a Premium plan to access live chat assistance. You can choose from thousands of plugins and themes on WordPress.org. With WordPress.com, you can only use plugins if you have a Business plan or higher. Advanced customization features are not available without a Premium package. You can choose from thousands of plugins and themes on WordPress.org. With WordPress.com, you can only use plugins if you have a Business plan or higher. Advanced customization features are not available without a Premium package. You can almost completely control your SEO strategies with WordPress.org. Yoast SEO is a plugin that can help you optimize your posts and pages for selected keywords. WordPress.com, on the other hand, has limited options for SEO. For Google Analytics integration, you will need a Premium subscription. Further, advanced SEO tools aren't available without a Business plan or higher. Thus, your website can't be optimized by cheaper packages. You can almost completely control your SEO strategies with WordPress.org. Yoast SEO is a plugin that can help you optimize your posts and pages for selected keywords. WordPress.com, on the other hand, has limited options for SEO. For Google Analytics integration, you will need a Premium subscription. Further, advanced SEO tools aren't available without a Business plan or higher. Thus, your website can't be optimized by cheaper packages.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What do you mean by importers in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Importers are WordPress tools that can move content from an existing WordPress site to a new one. A site can also be moved from localhost to an online server with this tool. Different data can be migrated using the WordPress importer. A few examples include: Pages, posts, and other types of custom posts\nCustom fields and post meta\nComments\nTags, Categories\nAuthors, etc. Pages, posts, and other types of custom posts Custom fields and post meta Comments Tags, Categories Authors, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. How can I adjust the default length of an excerpt in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Excerpts are parts of posts linking to full articles. In this way, readers are enticed to continue reading. It is helpful to highlight the important parts of your content since titles alone are not enough to capture readers' attention. Excerpts are limited to the first 55 words of your posts, but you can change the excerpt length either manually or with a WordPress plugin. The manual method usually involves editing the code, but you don't need to be an expert in any programming language to do this. Changing the default length of the excerpt in WordPress requires us to add the following syntax to the functions.php file and edit the number of words we wish to appear in the excerpt. function changed_excerptlength($length){\nreturn X;\n}\nadd_filter(‘excerpt_length’, ‘changed_excerptlength’); function changed_excerptlength($length){\nreturn X;\n}\nadd_filter(‘excerpt_length’, ‘changed_excerptlength’); Here, X is the number of excerpt words to be displayed.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Explain avatar and gravatar in WordPress.",
        "answer": "In the case of WordPress blogs or business websites, putting a face to your content will help your visitors connect and become more engaged. A good way of accomplishing this is with an avatar, a picture identifying you across your website. An avatar gives your site a more personal touch and lets users get to know you better. Using Gravatar, WordPress provides its users with avatars. Gravatar is an acronym for Globally Recognized Avatar. The Gravatar platform allows users to upload an image and use that image as their avatar on various websites. Gravatar images are displayed alongside comments, posts, and various other website activities.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. Can you tell me why widgets don't display in the sidebar?",
        "answer": "To add a widget, users must first verify that the themes they are using support it. It is possible that the problem could be caused by the absence of function.php or a file similar to it. Another possibility is that the user forgot to save the changes they made to the widget or did not refresh the older page display.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Explain shortcode in WordPress.",
        "answer": "A shortcode is a small chunk of code, placed between brackets like [yourshortcode], that performs a specific function for your site. It can be placed anywhere to provide a specific feature to a page, post, or other content. WordPress shortcodes make it easy to add dynamic content to pages, posts, and sidebars. Several WordPress plugins and themes offer shortcodes for adding specialized content to websites, such as sliders, image galleries, contact forms, and more.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is the best way to display a list of child pages in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Shortcodes are convenient, but they require you to add them to every page that has a parent or a child page. You may end up using shortcodes on a lot of pages, and you may even forget to do it. It would be beneficial to alter the page template file in your theme so that child pages will be displayed automatically. This can be achieved by editing the main page.php template, or by creating a custom page template in your theme.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Is it possible to check whether a featured image exists in WordPress?",
        "answer": "The has_post_thumbnail() method can be used to determine whether the featured image is present. Example: Example: if ( has_post_thumbnail() ) \n{\n    the_post_thumbnail();\n} if ( has_post_thumbnail() ) \n{\n    the_post_thumbnail();\n}",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Can you explain the user metafunction in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A user meta in WordPress is a set of distinct, different, and customized text fields for each user according to his or her preferences. In other words, WordPress user meta allows you to add whatever information you wish about your users. Update_user_meta() is the function you use to add or update a user's metadata. It looks as follows: update_user_meta( $user_id, $meta_key, $meta_value, $prev_value ); update_user_meta( $user_id, $meta_key, $meta_value, $prev_value ); Here, $user_id: User's ID to be affected.\n$meta_key: Name of user meta field to be altered.\n$meta_value: The value to be assigned to the user meta field. You may use integer, string, array, etc.\n$prev_value: Used for handling duplicate meta keys. Normally you can omit this option. $user_id: User's ID to be affected. $user_id: $meta_key: Name of user meta field to be altered. $meta_key: $meta_value: The value to be assigned to the user meta field. You may use integer, string, array, etc. $meta_value: $prev_value: Used for handling duplicate meta keys. Normally you can omit this option. $prev_value:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What are widgets in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A WordPress widget can be used to add specific content or features to a website. Website widgets can be added to various parts of a site, such as the sidebars or footer, or any other areas. Widgets allow you to add features and functions to your site with no programming required. There are many widgets you can add to your site, including menus, banner ads, calendars, popular posts,  and social icons.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. In what situations does the plugin menu not appear on the WordPress website.",
        "answer": "When using free wordpress.com, users can't see the plugin menu because it's limited in plugin usage. Even users who do not have an administrator account will not be able to access the plugin menu.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What are WordPress Themes?",
        "answer": "In WordPress, a theme consists of a collection of files (stylesheets, graphics, and code) that dictate what your blog or website will look like. Depending on your theme, you can tweak everything from your site's layout to the link colors. While a theme can be thought of as a 'skin' for your site, they are incredibly powerful. Your website theme affects the appearance of your site, including the typography, layout, color scheme, and other design elements.   When you create a new WordPress website, it comes with a pre-installed theme, but you can change it in WordPress to match your industry and needs. The right theme can improve visitors' engagement, enhance the appearance of your website, and make it easier to use. Divi, Astra, OceanWP, etc., are the most popular and best WordPress themes available for download.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What is a Child theme in WordPress?",
        "answer": "A child theme inherits the functionality, features, and styling of the parent theme (WordPress theme). Child themes let you change small details of your site's appearance while still preserving the parent theme's appearance and functionality. The child theme is designed to inherit the features and appearance of the parent theme, while also enabling the user to make modifications/alterations to any part of the theme.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. Explain WordPress Taxonomies.",
        "answer": "WordPress Taxonomies group content or data together in WordPress. Shortly, it allows you to organize/group your posts based on what they have in common (characteristics). Several default taxonomies are available, and you can also design your own. WordPress's Categories and Tags are two of its most popular taxonomies.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Explain Category and Tags in WordPress. How to convert a category into a tag?",
        "answer": "Categorization and tags play a much greater role in the content organization as well as SEO. Categories: Essentially, categories are a general way to group content on a WordPress website. The idea of a category is to represent a topic or a group of topics that are somehow related to one another. A post can belong to several categories at once. Nevertheless, assigning more than two or three categories to one post is perhaps not the best idea.\nTags: Tags provide a good way to identify a piece of content by specific keywords. Just choose a few words that best describe a given post. Categories: Essentially, categories are a general way to group content on a WordPress website. The idea of a category is to represent a topic or a group of topics that are somehow related to one another. A post can belong to several categories at once. Nevertheless, assigning more than two or three categories to one post is perhaps not the best idea. Categories: Tags: Tags provide a good way to identify a piece of content by specific keywords. Just choose a few words that best describe a given post. Tags:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. What are meta tags?",
        "answer": "Meta tags are snippets of HTML code that describe the content of a website or a specific webpage. Search engines use these bits of data to determine what a page is about, and they provide the content that shows up in search results. Although meta tags still provide the description displayed in search engine results, they contribute greatly to improving CTRs (Click-Through Rates). Conclusion In today's social era, creating a good, appealing, and attractive website for any business is so common to attract and engage more customers. The solution to this problem is WordPress: an open-source Content Management System (CMS) that enables you to easily build your websites. WordPress has 60% of the market share among the top 3 content management systems, i.e., WordPress, Joomla, and Drupal. The newest version of WordPress is 5.9.3 and was released on April 5, 2022. Are you looking for an opportunity to advance in your career as a WordPress developer? Then this article will help you. As there is a massive demand for WordPress, there could be plenty more questions related to it. However, we have tried to cover most of them. Having read these interview questions and practiced more of them, you will gain confidence in your preparation and will be prepared to take that next step towards achieving your goal. Hopefully, we were able to address any questions or concerns you may have had. All the best with your future pursuits. Useful Resources WordPress Books\nBackend Developer Skills\nFront End Developer Interview Questions\nWeb Developer Interview Questions\nFull Stack Developer Interview Questions\nSoftware Engineering Interview Questions\nTechnical Interview Guide\nInterview Resources WordPress Books WordPress Books Backend Developer Skills Backend Developer Skills Front End Developer Interview Questions Front End Developer Interview Questions Web Developer Interview Questions Web Developer Interview Questions Full Stack Developer Interview Questions Full Stack Developer Interview Questions Software Engineering Interview Questions Software Engineering Interview Questions Technical Interview Guide Technical Interview Guide Interview Resources Interview Resources",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress is an Open Source Content Management System (CMS) and a blogging tool, based on PHP and MySQL. It is free of cost, and you can use it for any personal and commercial website.\nWordpress is the most popular blogging system and used for more than 60 million websites. It is licensed under GPL.\n\nMore Details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) Is a website on WordPress safe and secure?",
        "answer": "WordPress is safe and secure to operate. You need not worry about anything but, still, it is suggested to update your site with latest WordPress version to avoid hacking.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) Is there any limitation for WordPress website?",
        "answer": "WordPress can be used for e-commerce sites, membership sites, photo galleries and any other type of site you can think. Following are some disadvantages of WordPress:\nADVERTISEMENT\nUsing several plugins can make the website heavy to load and run.\nPHP knowledge is required to make modifications or changes in the WordPress website.\nSometimes software needs to be updated to keep the WordPress up-to-date with the current browsers and mobile devices. Updating WordPress version leads to loss of data, so a backup copy of the website is required.\nModifying and formatting the graphic images and tables is difficult.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) When was the Wordpress released initially? When is it announced as open source software?",
        "answer": "WordPress was initially released on 27th May 2003 by Matt Mullenweg and Mike Little. WordPress was announced as open source in October 2009.\nMore Details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What is the latest version of WordPress?",
        "answer": "The latest version of WordPress is 4.9.8 released on Aug 02, 2018.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What are the system requirements for installing WordPress?",
        "answer": "Database - MySQL 5.0 +\nWeb Server -\nWAMP (Windows)\nLAMP (Linux)\nXAMP (Multi-platform)\nMAMP (Macintosh)\nOperating System - Cross-platform\nBrowser Support - IE (Internet Explorer 8+), Firefox, Google Chrome, Safari, Opera\nPHP Compatibility - PHP 5.2+",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are the steps should be followed for installing WordPress?",
        "answer": "Download Wordpress from www.wordpress.org\nExtract the downloaded files and upload it on your web server or localhost.\nOpen your web browser and navigate to the WordPress file path. Then you see the first screen of the WordPress installer.\nIn the next step, please select your preferred language.\nIn the next step, you see the information needed for the database before proceeding the WordPress installation.\nenter the details of your Mysql database.\nWordpress checks the details provided by you and gives you a confirmation screen.\nIn the next step, you have to enter the administration details.\nAfter entering the administration details, click on \"Install WordPress\" button.\nAfter successful installation, you get a screen stating \"success.\" You can see the username and the password on this screen.\nEnter your username and password on the next screen and click 'login.'",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Dashboard menu: This component of home screen provides the navigation menu options for posts, media library, pages, and comments on the left side of the screen.\nScreen options: This component of the home screen display different types of widgets which can be shown or hidden on some screen. This component also contains the checkboxes to show or hide different screen options and also allow to customize sections on the admin screen.\nWelcome: This component of the home page help us to customize WordPress theme by clicking on the customize your site button. Also, the center column provides some of the useful links such as creating a page and view the front end of your web page, creating a blog post. Moreover, the last column contains links to the menus, widgets, settings related to comments.\nQuick Draft: This component of the home screen includes a mini post editor which is used to write, save, and publish the post from the admin dashboard. This include title of the draft followed by some notes about the draft and save it as a draft.\nWordpress news: This component of home screen displays the latest news regarding the latest software update of WordPress.\nActivity: This component of the home screen shows the latest comments, recent posts published. It also allows you to reply, edit, delete, approve, or disapprove the comments. You can also move comments to spam.\nAt a Glance: This component of home screen displays an overview of your blog?s posts, number of published posts and pages, and number of comments.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) Is it possible to SEO a WordPress site to show it on Google first page?",
        "answer": "WordPress has an inbuilt SEO search engine benefit. You can also have an additional plug-in in WordPress to help with SEO and rank on a favorite search engine like Google.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) What is the difference between character 23 and x23?",
        "answer": "Here 23 specifies the octal 23 and x23 determine the hex 23.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Hooks enable users to create WordPress themes or plug-ins with shortcode without changing the original files.\nThere are two types of hooks:\nAction hooks: Action hooks facilitate you to insert an additional code from an outside resource.\nFilter hooks: Filter hooks facilitate you to add content or text at the end of the post.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What are the most exciting and useful features of WordPress?",
        "answer": "These are the features which make WordPress very popular:\nEasy to install and upgrade\nIn-built SEO engine\nFree and easy theme selection\nFlexibility\nMultilingual- available in more than 70 languages\nOwn data- no unwanted advert on your website\nFlexibility and Easy publishing option",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) Why does WordPress use MySQL?",
        "answer": "Following are the reasons to use MySQL with WordPress:\nOpen source\nExtremely fast\nA widely available database server\nSupported by low-cost Linux hosting",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) How many tables are there in WordPress by default?",
        "answer": "At present version, there are about 11 tables in WordPress by default. You can check the number of tables in WordPress by phpMyAdmin.\nwp_commentmeta\nwp_comments\nwp_links\nwp_options\nwp_postmeta\nwp_posts\nwp_terms\nwp_term_relationships\nwp_term_taxonomy\nwp_usermeta\nwp_users\nNote: The number of tables may be changed with successive releases.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) What is by default prefix of WordPress tables?",
        "answer": "The wp_ is by default prefix of WordPress tables.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "In WordPress, all objects are passed by value.\nMore Details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) How can you call a constructor for a parent class?",
        "answer": "You can call a constructor for a parent class by this way:\nParents:: constructor($value)\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) In which cases, WordPress is not suitable for a website?",
        "answer": "These are some situations when WordPress is not recommended:\nIf the client is working on the non-CMS based project.\nFor sophisticated and innovative e-commerce sites.\nSites which require custom scripting solutions.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) Is WordPress the best CMS or any other CMS is better than WordPress?",
        "answer": "No doubt WordPress is good CMS, but Drupal and Joomla are considered better CMS than WordPress to work.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "org?",
        "answer": "Wordpress.com is relatively more secure than wordpress.org because they limit the themes and does not allow plugin's installation. However, security depends on the hosting company of your website and also what steps they are taking to prevent the security problems.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Posts allow you to write a blog and post it on your site. They are listed in reverse chronological order on the front page of your blog.\n\nMore Details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Pages are different from posts. They are static, and they do not change often. You can add pages containing information about you and your site.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is the difference between WordPress posts and pages?",
        "answer": "WordPress posts are content published on a site with an exact date and time. They can be categorized systematically by category and tags. They are listed in reverse chronological order on a website.\nWordPress pages are static and do not frequently change such as contact us, about us, privacy policy. They don?t have a date and time published. However, the database stores their published date and time.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is a loop in WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress uses PHP codes to display posts. This PHP code is known as a loop.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) How can you disable WordPress comment?",
        "answer": "You can disable the WordPress comment on the dashboard. On the panel, under the options- discussion you find \"Allow people to post the comment.\" Uncheck this to disable comment.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "26) How can you edit a WordPress comment?",
        "answer": "You can edit WordPress comment using the dashboard. From the panel, under the Comments option, select edit to edit a comment.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Comments by visitors on a post are not published directly unless the admin provides it. It is called moderation. To change comment moderation setting, select Settings option from the dashboard and check the option \"Comment must be manually approved.\"\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "28) How to allow only registered users to comment on WordPress?",
        "answer": "If you don't want a comment from a new user on your blog, check the option \"Users must be registered and logged in to comment\" from Discussions under the Settings option.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Word Avatar is used for a user's profile image in online communications. Gravatar is a web-based service which allows its users to use the Avatar image.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) How can you handle the situation if your WordPress site is hacked?",
        "answer": "You should follow these steps:\nInstall security plugins like WP security\nRe-install the latest version of WordPress\nChange password and user-ids for all your users\nCheck your themes and plug-ins are up to date\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Categories allow a user to divide its content into different sections. Different topics publishing on a single website can be divided into different groups. It tells a reader what a post is about and they can easily find their content from a lot.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) How to convert a category into the tag?",
        "answer": "WordPress provides you an option to change category into tag and tag into a category. For this, you need to install Categories and Tags Converter from Import option under Tools section.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "With the help of tags, similar posts can be grouped. Hence, it makes more comfortable for the users to search for a particular post. Tags are similar to categories but still different.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "WordPress Categories are broad-ranging. It helps a user to identify about a blog. It is possible for a post to have more than one category. A post must have at least one category.\nWordPress Tags are like categories, but they are used to describe a post more specifically. Tags are not necessary for every post.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) How many types of users WordPress have?",
        "answer": "WordPress user role determines access permission to the users of a WordPress site.\nAdministrator: They have full rights over a site.\nEditor: They deal with the content section of a website.\nAuthor: They only deal with their posts. They can delete their post even after publishing.\nContributor: A contributor doesn't have the right to publish their post or page. They need to send it to the administrator for review.\nSubscriber: Users who are subscribed to your site can log in and update their profile.\nFollower: They don't have any right. They can only read and comment on your post.\nViewer: They can only read and comment on a post.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) What are WordPress Themes?",
        "answer": "With the help of a WordPress theme, you can design the layout and appearance of your website in the front-end.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) How will you select a WordPress theme?",
        "answer": "WordPress theme should complement your site. It can be either free or paid. An ideal theme should have qualities like simple, responsive, supports plugins, SEO friendly.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) What is the difference between custom themes and normal themes?",
        "answer": "Custom themes are very straightforward to format. You don't need much technical knowledge to change in the coding part. The custom theme allows for SEO search, but with an SEO plugin available it would not make much difference to a normal theme.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) What is the difference between free and paid WordPress theme?",
        "answer": "Free and premium WordPress themes are different in many ways. With free themes, you have to compromise with the quality as many other sites using the same theme. Problems in premium themes solved more quickly than in free themes.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "40) What are WordPress Plugins?",
        "answer": "WordPress plugins are programs written in PHP scripting language that extends the functionality or add some new features to a WordPress site. They provide additional functions to an application.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) When will you not be able to see the plugin menu on a WordPress site?",
        "answer": "When a site is hosted on free wrodpress.com, plugin menu will not appear. Also if you don't have an account for the administrator level, you can't see the plugin menu.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) What are the plugins you can use to create a contact form in WordPress?",
        "answer": "You can use a plug-in like Gravity forms or a free plugin contact form 7 to create a contact form in WordPress.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "A theme is an external effect of a website's presentation and designing. Whereas, a plugin is an interior effect which adds or remove some functions to a site.\nYou can customize some functionality in themes instead of installing the plugin, but plugins can't replace themes.\nMore details...",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) How to update a WordPress site?",
        "answer": "You should always update your site to the latest version of WordPress. Whenever there is a new WordPress version, you receive an update message on your admin screen.\nThere are two methods to update a WordPress site:\nOne-click update\nManually update",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Security in a WordPress site is essential as these websites are favorite targets for hackers. A site can't be perfectly secured, but one can at least reduce the risk by applying different security measures.\nSome of the measures to secure a WordPress site are given below:\nChoosing a host\nStrong password\n2 step login authentication\nLimit number of login attempts\nUse SSL\nKeep site updated",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "46) How to reset password in WordPress?",
        "answer": "If you forget or lost the password of your account, WordPress gives you an option to reset it through different methods.\nThere are four ways to reset WordPress password:\nChange password from the dashboard\nReset password via email\nManually reset the password through database via PhpMyAdmin\nUsing emergency password reset script",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "47) How to optimize WordPress site performance?",
        "answer": "Optimization increases the speed of your site and gives the best possible outcome. It improves the ranking of a website.\nThere are many tricks to optimize a WordPress site. Some of them are given below:\nUse CDN\nUse a caching plugin\nUse a simple theme/framework\nKeep site updated\nSplit long posts into smaller pages",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "48) What are template tags in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Template tags are used within themes to retrieve content from your database. It is a piece of code that tells WordPress to get something from the database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "49) What are meta-tags in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Meta-tags are keyword and description used to display website or page information.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "50) What are custom fields in WordPress?",
        "answer": "Custom fields are also called post meta. It is a feature through which users can add arbitrary information when writing a post. These metadata can be displayed using template tags in WordPress themes.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "51) How to take the backup of a WordPress site?",
        "answer": "A backup is just the copy of your original site through which you can restore your original site if anything goes wrong. Keeping a backup on the safe side is always advisable.\nA site is generally made up of two parts. One is all the installed themes/plugins, media and other is Database which stores all your blogs, posts, and comments. Without files, there is no site, and without the database, there is no data. Hence both of them is important and need a backup.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "52) Why is Backup important?",
        "answer": "Backup allows you to retrieve your site back if something goes wrong or if your site breaks. There could be many reasons for this like external attack, hacking, server down.\nYou can lose everything from data to all the posts on your site. The backup is essential to avoid it.\nSecuring your backup is also an important issue. Make sure to update your plugins and themes regularly or in a specified interval. Use strong Username and Password. Database name should also be uncommon.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "53) How to Backup WordPress root Files?",
        "answer": "There are many files in your WordPress directory. These files can be downloaded back from wordpress.org site. Some of them can be retrieved back but some can't.\nThe wp-content directory contains all your installed themes and plugins including all your media files like images, audio or video files which you uploaded on your site. Hence, it makes it personal and unique.\n\nThe wp-config.php file consists of your Database and other personnel options which make it also a unique file.\nBoth the above files can't be replaced by other default files. Hence, they need to be backed up.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "",
        "answer": "In the database, all your posts, media files, comments, and metadata stored. It also contains user's information and all your plugin settings. All these information are personal and unique. If you lose them, they are gone permanently. Select your WordPress database (which you created during the installation of WordPress).\nClick on Export.\nQuick is used when the database is small. Custom is used when the database is large. Suppose we are choosing Custom.\nAfter choosing Custom, a table appears. Select all the tables.\nNow come to the Output section.\nChoose SQL from the Format drop-down menu.\nCheck \"Add drop table.\" It is useful for overwriting an existing table.\nCheck \"If not exists.\" It prevents errors when tables are already there.\nNow click Go. Your data will be saved in your system.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "55)Which licensing authority is responsible for WordPress?",
        "answer": "WordPress is licensed under GPLv2 (GNU General Public License) which makes it free and open-source software. Each copy of WordPress has a licensed copy with it.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    },
    {
        "question": "56) What is GNU?",
        "answer": "The GNU General Public License is called GPL in short. It has some terms and conditions to copy, modify and distribute the software licensed under its name.\nGNU makes sure that any software source-code licensed under it has to make originating source code open and freely available to all its users. Here, freely doesn't mean by cost but it says that it is freely available to users to distribute and modify the code, but they can't impose any restrictions on further distribution, the source code has to be made available.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "wordpress"
    }
]